放松一点, 操作时别那么紧张
Ease up on the controls a little.
我很好
I'm fine.
你要把那该死的东西拔下来了, 放松一点
You're going to snap the damn things off. Ease up.
我只是想看看这个baby能做些什么
I'm justy seeing what this baby can do.
你刚才叫它"baby"?
Did you just say "this baby"?
这非常接近宇航员们的说法
It's perfectly appropriate space pilot parlance.
尽量把这个"baby"沿直线飞行
Just try to fly the baby in a straight line.
我是沿直线飞行来着
I'm flying in a straight line.
不完全是
Not so much.
好吧, 在太空中, 所有的运动都是相关的
Well, in space, all motion is relative.
你还好吧, Gall博士?
You okay, Dr. Gall?
我有点晕, 只要是在动的东西里面
I get motion sickness.
这些东西有惯性阻尼器
These things have inertial dampeners.
你不应该会觉察到移动的
You shouldn't feel a thing.
我...我知道我们在动
I...I know we're moving.
这对我来说已经足够了
That's enough for me.
我为什么选这个人来执行任务?
Why'd you choose this guy for the mission?
是Brendan发现了那个处于拉格朗日点的卫星
Brendan's the one who discovered
the lagrangian point satellite was out here.
Elizabeth认为只有他可以找到它
Elizabeth felt he should see it for himself.
不要放开操作杆!
Don't let go of the controls!
不需要一直抓住吧!
Snapping doesn't help!
这就是为什么父母亲总是请别人来教他们的孩子如何驾驶
This is why parents get someone else
to teach their kids how to drive.
嗨, 你这句话真是让我又受伤又感动
Hey, I'm both insulted and touched by that.
噢, 我的天哪
Oh, my god.
McKay...
是的, 是的, 当然, 请吧
Yes, yes, of course, please.
在距离1000米远的地方停住
Holding station at 1,000 meters.
我们差不多在半英里远的地方
然后它却充满了整个挡风玻璃, 这个东西真是大啊
We're almost a half a mile away and it's
filling the windshield. This thing is enormous.
它有Goa'uld母舰那么大了
It's as large as a Goa'uld mothership.
这可能是独立武器平台中最大的了
This might be the single largest
weapons platform ever constructed.
这可能是古人在Atlantis之前的最后防线了
It's probably the ancients' last line
of defense before Atlantis.
它还有可能在运转起来么?
这可是一个非常好的东西
Any chance it's still operational?
Because that would be a very good thing.
你那有没有得到能量读数?
Are you getting any energy readings?
没有
Negative.
就是说这玩意儿死了?
So it's dead?
好吧, 这需要进一步深入调查, 不过现在可以这么说
Well, it warrants closer scrutiny, but yeah.
在古人们最后一次防守中被攻破了?
Knocked out during the ancients' last stand?
要么它的能源用完了
一万年可不短啊
Or its power source is depleted.
10,000 years is a long time.
- 我们需要靠近去看看...
- 等等
- We should still take a closer look...
- Wait, wait.
我在超低频段收到一些信号
I'm getting something in the ultra-low frequency range.
从哪里来的?
Where's it coming from?
这个行星
The planet.
这是一个求救信号...
It's a distress call...
幽灵的求救信号
A Wraith distress call.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第12集 抵抗
Season 1 : Episode 12 The Defiant One
你确定是幽灵么?
You're sure it's Wraith?
在这个太阳系中?
In this solar system?
更简单的说, 它就在我们的后院
I know. Celestially speaking,
it's right in our backyard.
我认为是古人的卫星把幽灵的飞船击落了
We figure the ancient satellite
shot the Wraith ship down
在保卫Atlantis的最后战斗中
in the final battle for Atlantis.
而它在几千年后仍然在发出信号?
And it's still putting out a signal
after thousands of years?
非常微弱的信号
It's a very weak signal.
听我说, 如果这艘飞船的还有部分仍然保持完好
Look, if any part of that ship is intact,
那就还有科学上和军事上的研究价值
the wealth of scientific and military knowledge
这种价值是无法估量的
we could acquire is invaluable.
那么你的意思是?
So what are you saying?
我们必须下去瞧瞧
We have to go down and take a look.
必须去?
You have to?
你们花了15个小时才到达那里
It took you almost 15 hours to get there.
好吧, 另外一个我们必须去看看的原因是
Well, all the more reason we should have a look.
我们已经在这里了
We're already here.
我必须提醒的是这个行星的大气层已经极度电离化了
I should mention that the planet's
atmosphere is extremely ionized.
无线电通信将会非常困难
Radio communication could be difficult.
即使我们派出救援
也要花15小时才能赶到这里
And it would take at least 15 hours
to send out any sort of rescue.
我们会没事的
We'll be fine.
少校?
Major?
我同意McKay
I agree with McKay.
你当然同意
Of course you do.
你们当中有谁会放弃探索一个坠毁的外星飞船的机会呢?
How could either of you resist exploring
a crashed alien spaceship?
很对
Exactly.
我向你保证, 这些兴趣完全
是为了我们的工作, Elizabeth.
I assure you, our interest
is purely professional, Elizabeth.
认真的说, 我们可以从他们的武器系统中
得到不少东西...
Seriously, the amount of intel we could
gather from their weapons system...
密码, 防护罩...
Codes, shields...
好吧
All right.
那一定要非常小心
Proceed with extreme caution, please,
三小时之内要跟我联系
and check in with me in three hours.
- 三小时? 太短了点吧...
- 没问题
- Three hours? That's hardly enough time...
- Will do.
探索者1号出发
Jumper one out.
"无线电通信会非常困难"
"Radio communication could be difficult."
嗨, 她同意了, 不是么?
Hey, she said yes, didn't she?
这不是你的功劳
And no thanks to you.
好吧, 你们可以停一下了, 伙计们
All right, knock it off, guys.
我花了15个小时听你们两个唠叨
I've spent the last 15 hours listening to you two.
准备好了么?
Are we ready?
好吧, 记住我们降落的位置
All right, let's remember where we parked.
我们为什么不降落在飞船附近?
Why didn't we just land next to the ship?
以防万一
Just a precaution.
万一什么?
现在离它坠毁已经有几千年了
A precaution for what?
The Wraith ship crashed thousands of years ago.
自动防御
Automated defenses.
我从来没有想过
I never thought of that.
没事, Brendan.
Don't worry, Brendan.
我们研究的领域不同
We weren't all built for field work.
我们快到了, 是么?
Seriously, we're almost there, right?
这是什么?
What's that?
某种虫子?
Some kind of bug?
太空虫
Space bug.
它正在发出某种相当强烈的生命信号
It's giving off
some pretty strong life-signs readings.
啊, 我想我对蜜蜂之类的东西比较过敏
Uh, okay, did I mention
how allergic I was to bee stings?
可能它闻到了食物的味道
Maybe it smells the food.
也许它刚刚闻到了少女的恐惧
Maybe he's just smelling the girlish fear.
好吧, 我们别管它, 它也不会理我们的
Well, let's leave it be, and it'll leave us be.
伙计们...
Guys...
你们以前看过类似的东西么?
Have you seen one like this before?
它太小了, 不可能是幽灵们群居的那种飞船
It's too small to be a hive ship.
它在这儿已经很久了
Well, it's been here for a very long time.
也许他们放弃了那种模式
Maybe they've discontinued that model.
可能吧, 不管它是什么, 这看起来像是地狱
Maybe, but whatever it is, it took a hell of a hit.
被古人卫星击落的那个
Score one for the ancient satellite.
那里仍然有一些骨架
There's still some skeletons down there.
我猜坠落后可能有人还活着
I guess everyone didn't die in the crash.
有任何生命的迹象么?
Are you getting any life signs?
我想我们没必要害怕
I think we can rule that out.
这只是以防万一
It's just a precaution.
好吧
Fine.
没有, 只有我们和那些发光的虫子
飞船那儿什么都没有
No, it's just us and the glowy bugs.
Nothing coming from the ship.
好的
Good.
我们去瞧瞧吧
Let's go take a look.
我收到了微弱的能量信号
I'm picking up faint power readings.
肯定有东西在为发射求救信号的装置提供能量
Something had to be powering the distress beacon.
来吧, Abrams.
Come on, Abrams.
也许我们应该派个人守在外面
Maybe one of us should stay outside.
好吧, 我知道你是怎么想的
Look, I know how you feel,
但是这种机会我们以后还会有么?
but how many opportunities like this
are we going to get?
看起来这个家伙好像刚刚才死去
This guy looks like he just lied there and died.
它被保存得很好
It's remarkably preserved.
要么就是它确实是不久前才死
Or it wasn't that long ago.
好吧
All right.
Beckett需要一些样本
Beckett will want samples.
谁来...?
It is...?
好吧
Yeah.
OK...
Okay...
这到底是...?
What the...?
OK
Okay.
这和往常不同
This is different.
幽灵嗜食同类?
Wraith cannibalism?
看起来是
Looks like it.
他们自相残杀?
They feed off each other?
这可能是最后的手段
Probably as a last resort.
我猜它们当中有人试图尽可能的活得久些
I guess some of them tried
to survive as long as possible.
好吧, 这真是难以置信
Okay, that is incredibly disturbing.
别开玩笑了
No kidding.
我想, 如果有...
You know, I wonder if there's...
伙计们!
Guys!
这是尸体, 人类的尸体
They're bodies, human bodies.
在他们群居的飞船也有类似的房间
They have chambers like this on hive ships.
但我以前从来没有见过这么大的
I've never seen one so large before.
我不明白
I don't understand.
幽灵把人封到茧中
The Wraith cocoon humans.
让他们的身体停止活动
这样将来就可以...
They keep their bodies in a sort of
suspended animation, so later they can...
我想我们已经知道了这艘船是干什么的了
I think we just figured out what this ship was for.
这是一艘补给船...
It's a supply ship...
给围困Atlantis的幽灵们补给食物
On its way to feed the Wraith who
were laying siege to Atlantis.
这太恐怖了
Well, that's terrifying.
Gall, Abrams, 检查一下, 要小心
Gall, Abrams, check it out, but be careful.
什么? 不, 等等
What? No, wait.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
好吧, 这艘船应该有驾驶台
也许可以在那找到些有用的东西
Well, the ship's got to have a bridge.
Maybe we can get some useful intel.
也就是说你要把我们留在这里?
So you're just leaving us here?
有什么问题么? 他们都死了
What's the problem? They're all dead.
这就是问题!
That's the problem!
就是用DV拍拍, 然后粗略数数人数
Just get some D.V. and a rough head count.
我们仍然可以用无线电联系
We'll stay in radio contact.
那可能会比较困难
飞船的这部分好像真的有屏蔽作用
That could be difficult.
This part of the ship seems really shielded.
Weir只给了我们几个小时
Weir only gave us a few hours.
我们每隔几分钟就联系一次
We'll check in every few minutes.
你不是想在某个领域研究么
You wanted field work.
这... 就是你要研究的
This... Is field work.
中尉, 我想让你带一队人待命
准备救援
Lieutenant, I'd like you to put a team
on standby for a rescue mission.
少校出了什么问题么?
Is the major all right?
一切都好, 我保证
I'm sure everything's fine.
我只是想有一队人准备着
I'd just like to have a team ready.
这就是说, 以防万一?
So just in case?
是的, 以防万一
Yeah. Just in case.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
在E.M.频谱我没有收到任何信号
I'm not picking up anything in the E.M. spectrum.
我本应该再带上一份能源
I may need to rig up a secondary power source
这样我们就可以接入他们的计算机系统
so we can interface with their computer systems.
我现在只是想知道...
I'm just thinking out loud here...
什么?
What?
如果有刚才发现的那些人提供食物
一个幽灵最多可以活多久?
How long do you think a Wraith could feed
on all those humans back there?
嗯, 在某些时候他们可以冬眠几百年
Well, they're capable of hibernating
for hundreds of years at a time,
但是, 我的意思是, 你想想
but, I mean, think about it.
一万年前人类文明才刚刚开始
10,000 years ago was roughly
the dawn of human civilization.
那, 它们有没有机会...
So there's no chance...
不会, 不会, 不会
你在开玩笑?
No, no, no. Are you kidding?
噢, 也有可能
Well... Maybe.
McKay
McKay.
不
No.
不, 在这种情况下没有生命可以活这么久
No, no living thing could survive
that long under those conditions.
这是荒谬的
It's ridiculous.
好吧
Okay.
那需要一个不可思议的能源
在整个这段时间内
That would require an incredible
power source capable of sustaining
将贮存的人类维持在僵化状态
the stored humans in suspended
animation almost the entire time.
那就是说这是可能的了?
So it's possible?
噢, 天哪. 这确实是可能的
Oh, my god. It is possible.
我们要快点离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
Gall, Abrams, 我是Sheppard.
Gall, Abrams, this is Sheppard.
少校, 你想吓死我么?
Major, are you trying to scare me to death?
我可能有些过于谨慎
但我们需要...
I'm probably being
a little overcautious, but we need to...
我们要做什么?
We need to what?
少校, 再说一次
刚才你的信号中断了
Major, say again. Your radio's breaking up.
我们撤回到入口处
Let's fall back to our point of ingress.
然后回到我们的飞船
We're headed back to the jumper.
我想我们需要离开这里
I think we're getting out of here.
我想我看到了什么, 在你身后的走廊上
I just saw something in the corridor behind you.
我们不能从那边走
We can't go that way.
少校, 我刚才看到了什么
Major, I just saw something.
好吧, 别动
All right, stay put.
我们就过来
We're coming back to you.
收到
Understood.
这儿什么都没有
There's nothing out here.
Brendan, 那只是你的错觉
Brendan, you're just freaking out on me.
我跟你说, 我确实看见了
I'm telling you, I saw something.
把那东西拿开, 你会杀了我的
Put that thing away. You're going to kill somebody.
我知道我看到了什么!
I know what I saw!
噢, 天哪
Oh, my god.
这边
This way.
他死了
He is dead.
Gall在哪?
Where's Gall?
不知道
I don't know.
Gall, 我是Sheppard. 回话
Gall, this is Sheppard. Come in.
它肯定把他带走了
It must have taken him.
你是对的 他们正在动
You're right. They're on the move.
我想干什么?
What're you doing?
带上他的武器和弹药, 拿着
Taking his weapons andd his ammo. Here.
- 我已经有支枪了
- 现在你有两支了
- I already have a gun.
- Now you have two.
你不是想去追那个幽灵吧?
You're not planning on going after the Wraith?
我想救出gall, 然后离开这个该死的地方
I plan on going after gall,
then I plan on getting the hell out of here.
在我检查的时候, 这里根本就没有生命信号
There was nothing alive when I scanned for life signs.
在它们冬眠的时候, 是不会显示生命信号的
They don't show up as life signs
when they're hibernating.
好吧. 我们走
Okay. Let's go.
求求你!
Please!
他们从不会迟到的
They're not even overdue yet.
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
把这称作直觉, 或者偏执
或者我们可以把这当作是一个训练
Call it intuition, paranoia,
or we can just call it a drill.
无论如何, 我希望你们马上出发
Either way, I want you to go now.
我们随时可以被召回
如果他们真的是碰上了麻烦...
We can always be called back,
but if they are in trouble...
那我们就不要浪费时间了
- Then every moment counts.
- Exactly.
Ford, 你的驾驶员是谁?
Ford, who's your pilot?
Markham
Markham.
好的, 他可以进行一些驾驶练习
Good, he could use some piloting practice.
我已经准备了大量的军火, 足以进行一场小型战争了
And I've packed enough ordnance to fight a small war.
希望最好不要这样
Let's hope you don't have to.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
我们出发吧
Let's move out.
那是什么?
What's that?
不知道, 但我想我没有带够弹药
I don't know, but I don't have
the ordnance I should have,
杀死那些人要用掉大量的弹药
and it takes a lot to kill these guys.
我要尽可能的多带些
I'll take any edge I can get.
你是从哪个星球来的?
What world are you from?
无论如何...你还是会杀了我的
Y-you're going to kill me anyway.
你是坐飞船过来的
You have come here by ship.
飞船在哪儿?
Where is it?
我说了你也会杀了我的
You're going to kill me anyway.
但我可以慢慢来
But not all at once.
好...待在我身后
Okay... Stay behind me.
除非我叫你, 千万别开火
Shoot only when I tell you to shoot.
他离开了飞船
He's left the ship.
它杀了Abrams.
It killed Abrams.
我们知道
We know.
它太快了...
It was so fast...
它还从我身上取食
It fed off me.
你会好起来的
You're going to be all right.
当时它正在夺走我的生命
It was taking my life.
我可以感觉得到...
I could feel it...
好了, 好了, 好了
听我说, 听我说
All right, all right, all right.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
你仍然还活着
You're still here.
你能动么?
Can you move?
肩膀下面都动不了了
Nothing below my shoulders.
我想麻痹只是暂时的
I'm sure the paralysis is just temporary.
几小时后, 你就会好起来的
You'll be all right in a few hours.
我把我们飞船所在的方位告诉它了
I told him where we left the jumper.
它还拿走了我的遥控器
He took my remote.
它不会把它飞走的
He won't be able to fly it.
你肯定?
Do we know that for a fact?
只有操作者拥有特定的基因, 古人的科技才能运作
I'm sure the Wraith were the main reason
我认为这主要是是为了防范幽灵
the ancient technology only works
if the operator has a specific gene.
无论如何, 他还是会夺走我们所有的武器, 食物和水...
Either way, he'll still have all of
our weapons, food, and water...
由它去吧
Who cares?
那如果它用我们的次空间无线电来通知它的同类呢?
What if he can use our subspace radio
to signal his friends?
它应该可以这么做
He might be able to do that.
那我要抢先赶过去
Not if I can get there first.
- 可它已经先去了
- 我会尽快的
He's got a head start. I can be pretty fast.
Elizabeth会派出另外一艘飞船的
我们只需要等一下...
Elizabeth will send another jumper.
We just need to wait...
你跟他在一起
Stay with him.
不, 请不要丢下我们
No. Please don't leave us.
他是对的, 我们应该呆在一起
He's right. We should stick together.
它杀了Abrams.
He killed Abrams.
跟你一样, 我也很难过
但这只是由于我们都犯了一个错误...
I'm as sorry about that as you are,
but just because we both made an error...
我没时间跟你争论这个!
I don't have time to argue about this!
现在, 把你的无线电设置到二频道
Now, set your radio to channel two,
不过你不要用它, 除非我呼叫你
but don't use it till you hear from me.
少校
Major.
少校!
Major!
没事儿, 这只是...
It's fine, just...
OK
Okay.
看到什么了?
Anything?
没有
No.
希望只有这一个
Hopefully there's just the one.
你不会让我在这等死, 对么?
You're not going to let me die out here, are you?
当然, 不要胡思乱想了
No, don't be ridiculous.
你明白, 我看得出来
You know, because people would talk.
你为什么要那么做?
And why would they do that?
这很明显
It's obvious.
你害怕我会超越你
You're afraid I'll outshine you.
我的意识, 我的青春...
My mind. My youth...
它到底夺走了我多少生命力?
How much of my life did he take?
你看起来很好
You look fine.
因为这就是它们所做的, 是不是?
它们夺走了你几十年生命
Because that's what they do, isn't it?
They take years off of your life.
我看起来很老, 是不是?
I look old, don't I?
你看起来老了一些, 是的
You look older, yes.
让我看看
Show me.
没有必要
There's no point in doing this.
- 你只是...
- Rodney.
- You just...
让我看看
Show me.
噢, 我的天啊!
Oh, my god!
我不知道这是怎么搞的, Brendan.
我想没人知道
I don't know how it works, Brendan.
I don't think anybody does.
也许你并没有真正的变老
也许这跟平常的衰老机制不一样...
Maybe you haven't really aged.
Maybe it doesn't work that way.
听我说, 有可能, 将来, 你会好起来的
Look, it's possible that,
in time, you could get better.
现在重要的是你还活着
The important thing is that you're still alive.
现在你可以动了么?
Can you move yet?
我想我的手脚已经开始有知觉了
I think I'm starting to get
some feeling back in my extremities.
好的, 那就好
Well, there's something.
怎么?
What?
我只是想在这帮帮忙
I'm just trying to help here.
瞧, 是你找到了那个昏迷不醒的的卫星
Look, you're the one who had
to find the stupid satellite.
哈, 不要逗我笑了
Ah, don't make me laugh.
Yeah. 你不应该笑
Yeah. You shouldn't laugh.
这... 这不是很好
It's... It's not so good.
已经六个小时了. 他们仍然没有联系
It's been six hours. They still haven't checked in.
还好我们已经在路上了
Good thing we left when we did.
要小心, 中尉
Be careful, Lieutenant.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
Gall说过在那个星球上用无线电可能会有问题
Gall said something about radio
being a problem on the surface,
所以, 希望这只是由于
他们飞船上的次空间通信无法工作
so, hopefully, the jumper's subspace
communications are just down.
我们已经准备好去做我们该做的了
We're prepared to do whatever we need to do.
你已经在这个太阳系的另外一边了, 中尉
You're on the other side of
the solar system, Lieutenant.
你所说的就要变成现实了
It's going to be your call.
是的, 夫人, 是这样
Yes, ma'am, it is.
McKay
McKay.
在
We're still here.
这个狗娘养的赢了. 它太快了
The son of a bitch beat me to it. He's fast.
那你应该回到这来
Then you should get back here.
不行
Negative.
你在外面毫无意义...
There's no point in you being out there...
他在我的飞船上
He's aboard my ship.
那又怎样, kirk船长?
What are you, Captain kirk?
他又能把飞船怎样?
What good's it going to do him?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许它可以短接导线, 启动飞船
我也不想冒险
Maybe he can hotwire the damn thing.
I don't want to take a chance.
你知道这个星球上的白天有多长么?
Do you have any idea how long
the days are on this planet?
不知道. 干什么?
No. Why?
因为我感觉到这里的夜晚将会非常寒冷
零度以下的寒冷
Because I've got a feeling the nights
are pretty damn cold, sub-zero cold.
我们已经迟到六个小时了
We're six hours overdue.
假设他们等了一个小时, 然后开始了救援行动...
Assuming they waited an hour
before sending a rescue mission...
在救援飞船到来之前这里很可能会天黑
There's a very good chance it's going to
be dark before another jumper can get here.
如果我们玩等待游戏的话
那这个在这里呆了一万年的家伙就会赢
If we play the waiting game, the guy who's
been around  for 10,000 years is going to win.
少校, 不管怎么说
他有能力活那么久
Major, anyone or anything
capable of surviving that long
也就是说明他不是那么好就可以对付的
is going to be a serious adversary.
是的, 除非我把引出到开阔地
Well, not if I get him out in the open.
它不会明白我们的武器
He won't know about our weapons.
如果不出意外, 我将会把飞船飞回来接你们
If all goes well, I'll fly the jumper
back and pick you up.
那如果出了意外呢?
And if all doesn't go well?
不会的
It will.
事情不可能进行得如此顺利的
Things haven't gone all that well thus far.
你知道, Rodney, 如果你有足够的火力的话
这些家伙还是会死的
You know, Rodney, these guys do die
if you have enough firepower.
好吧, 最终, 是的, 但是...
Well, eventually, yes, but...
试图往好的方面想想
Try and stay positive.
Gall感觉怎么样了?
How's gall feeling?
他可以动他的脚趾了
His can move his toes.
瞧, 一切都在往好的方向发展
See? Things are looking up.
我是John Sheppard少校
This is major John Sheppard.
你正在把我的飞船弄得乱七八糟
我要你把它们都弄回原样
That's my ship you're messing with. I'd like it back.
这是Lantian人的飞船
This ship is Lantian.
是的, 它是
Yes, it is.
Lantians已经位于战败的边缘了
The Lantians were on the verge of defeat.
好吧, 你不了解战争的结局
Well, you weren't around for the end of the war.
你那边战败了
Your side lost.
不可能
Impossible.
这是真的
It's true.
你现在是同类中的最后一个了
You're the last of your kind.
他们的城市被包围了
Their city was under siege.
他们只剩下了Atlantis
Atlantis was all that remained.
胜利是必然的
Victory was inevitable.
好吧, 你自己也看到了
我的飞船是Lantian人的
Well, you can see for yourself my ship is Lantian.
我还活着证明我们仍然在周围
不过幽灵全部都死光了
I'm living proof we're still around,
but the Wraith were all gone.
除了你, 再没有其他幽灵了
No one's left but you.
你说的不会是真的
What you say cannot be true.
你为什么不下来回到你自己的飞船亲自看看?
Why don't you come down to your
own ship and see for yourself?
我会一直等着你
I'll be waiting for you.
你别想打败我!
You cannot hope to defeat me!
看, 我是怎么跟你说的, aha?
There. What'd I tell you, huh?
Rodney, 我感觉不是很好
Rodney, I don't feel so good.
水
Water.
可能需要一些水
Probably need some water.
McKay...
少校, 发生什么了?
Major, what's happening?
我想你应该知道...
I thought you should know...
第一回合打了个平手
Round one was a draw.
我不喜欢这种声音
I don't like the sound of that.
我也不喜欢. 我着火了
Me neither. I took some fire.
你受伤了么?
Are you injured?
是的, 这就是我说"我着火了"的意思
Yeah, that's what I mean by "I took some fire."
不过我想还不算坏
但是我的P-90不能用了
But I don't think it's too bad,
but my P-90's out of commission.
他在飞船中找到了一支9-mil
而且很快就学会了如何使用它
He found a 9-mil in the jumper,
figured out how to use it pretty fast.
好吧, 幽灵可以治愈它自己
Well, the Wraith will heal itself.
别开玩笑
No kidding.
我至少射了20发子弹在他身上
而且还有额外补了两发
I put at least 20 shot into him,
and a couple more for good measure.
我看到幽灵倒下了
而且在我靠近时仍然倒在地上
I've seen Wraith go down and stay down with far less.
这个家伙有点不一样
This guy's different somehow.
Beckett博士已经研究出
幽灵可以治愈它们自己
Dr. Beckett has theorized that
a Wraith's ability to heal itself
而这直接取决于它上次进食的时间
而这个幽灵...
is directly proportional to how
recently the Wraith has fed, and he's...
刚刚才进食
Fed pretty recently.
我想可能还不止这些
I think there's got to be more to it than that.
Gall可以动他的手指了么?
Can Gall move his fingers yet?
刚刚可以
Barely.
好的, 那就塞一支枪到他的手里
All right, then stick a gun in his hand.
少校?
Major?
只是怕万一我回不来了
Just in case I don't make it back.
Sheppard出局了
Sheppard out.
这很令人鼓舞, huh?
That's comforting, huh?
好吧, 水
All right. Water.
噢, 该死!
Oh, crap!
少校, 到底是怎么回事?
Major, what the hell was that?
我差点把我自己炸死
I almost blew myself up.
什么?
What?
别说了, 我很忙
Stay off the radio. I'm busy.
好吧
Right.
他很忙
He's busy.
你想出去帮他, 是么?
You want to get out there and help him, don't you?
什么? 让我去对付一个幽灵? 你不是开玩笑吧?
What? Me go up against a Wraith? Are you kidding?
你是这样想的, 我知道
You do, I can tell.
你已经变了
You've changed.
你真的很想出去
You really want to get out there.
- 住嘴
- 别阻止我
- Shut up.
- Don't get me wrong.
我很感动
I'm impressed.
你想出去战斗
You want in the fight.
我原先所了解的Rodney McKay将...
The Rodney McKay I knew would never...
你也听到他说的了, 我们都要呆在这里
You heard the man. We're staying right here.
对
Right.
拿住这个, 不过除非我叫你,
不要朝任何东西射击, 明白?
Take this, but don't shoot at anything
until I tell you to, okay?
明白
Okay.
你想要这个?
You want some of this?
好了, 好了, 够了
Okay, okay. That's enough.
你是对的, 我必须出去
You're right. I should go out there.
我没有说你必须这样做
I didn't say you should.
我知是说你想这么做
I said you wanted to.
因为我必须这样做
Because I should.
不, 你没有必要
No, you shouldn't.
不过不要让我妨碍你
But don't let me stop you.
如果你真的认为你出去可以帮助少校的话...
If you really think you can help
the major by going out...
我不能让你留在这儿
I can't leave you here.
不, 你可以
Yes, you can.
这有什么不同么?
What difference does it make?
你和我都知道我活不了了
You and I both know I'm not going to make it.
别胡说了
Stop being so dramatic.
每一分钟, 你都在变得更加强壮
You're getting stronger by the minute.
我从来没有感到如此虚弱过
I've never felt so weak.
那就不要讲话了
Then stop talking.
我要死了, Rodney. 我可以感觉得到
I'm dying, Rodney. I can feel it.
住嘴!
Stop it!
我不会好了, 我正变得越来越虚弱
I'm not getting better. I'm getting worse.
它留给我一小部分生命
好让你留在这里看着我死
He left me with just enough life
so that you'd have to watch me die.
听我说
Listen to me.
你需要的只是一餐好饭, 一壶茶, 和停止说话, 然后...
All you need is a good meal,
a pot of tea, and to stop talking, and...
Brendan!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我说过不要讲话了
You said to stop talking.
我很抱歉, 我原以为你已经...
I'm sorry, I thought you'd...
抱歉
Apologies.
做得对
Nice work.
现在不行, 伙计们
Not now, guys.
我们大概可以进行无线电联系了, 长官
We may be able to make radio contact now, sir.
少校, 我是Ford中尉. 回话
Major, this is lieutenant Ford. Come in.
少校, 我们一小时内就到
请回答
Major, we should be there inside an hour.
Please respond.
也许我们仍然离得太远
Perhaps we're still too far away.
要么就是他们在那个星球上收不到信号
Or maybe they can't get a signal on the planet.
看看你能不能让这个东西跑得更快一点
See if you can make this thing go a little faster.
你认为我是一个白痴么, Sheppard少校?
Do you think I'm a fool, Major Sheppard?
在这个星球上, 你无处可去
There is nowhere for you to go on this world.
当我吃你的时候
我会好好品尝你反抗的滋味的
When I feed upon you,
I will savor the taste of your defiance.
嗨, 你
Hey, you.
在这儿
Over here.
在地上, 无线电
On the ground, the radio.
这个星球的白天很长
不过夜晚非常寒冷
The days on this planet are long,
but the nights are cold.
迟早...
Sooner or later...
我会抓住你
I will have you.
想把我的生命从我的身体中吸出来?
除非你按一下无线电上的按钮, 否则我听不到你的威胁
I can't hear you threatening to suck the life out
of me till you hit the button on the radio.
你听到了么?
Did you hear that?
没有
No.
我想我听到了什么
I thought I heard something.
可能还有一个正在冬眠
Maybe there's another one hibernating.
不是
No.
太久了
It's been too long.
我想少校可能碰到了麻烦
如果他碰到了麻烦, 那我们就麻烦了
I think the major could be in trouble,
and if he's in trouble, we're in trouble.
那就去吧
Then go.
你认为你可以动了么?
Do you think you could move?
不行
Not a chance.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
好吧
Okay.
没事
That's okay.
去吧
Go.
Rodney, 快去吧
Rodney, just go.
拯救这一天
Save the day.
我真正想做的就是通过无线电呼叫他
What I really want to do is call him on the radio,
但是我怕他正在躲避幽灵
but I'm afraid if he's hiding from the Wraith,
我可能不经意间暴露了他的位置
I might inadvertently give away his position,
让我们面对现实吧
如果Sheppard不能把幽灵除掉, 我们还有多少机会?
and let's face it, what chance would we have
against the Wraith if Sheppard can't take him out?
我曾想你可以恢复过来, 这样我...
I was hoping you'd be strong that I...
不, 不
Oh, no.
你一定是在跟我开玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
我已经吃了不计其数的人类和lantians
甚至是我的同类
I have fed upon countless thousands of humans
and lantians, even upon my own crew,
而且我可以在今天结束之前吃掉你
and I will feed upon you before this day is done.
少校, 我是Ford中尉
请回答
Major, this is lieutenant Ford. Please respond.
中尉, 你来得太及时了
Lieutenant, I like your timing.
快点过来
Get your ass down here.
长官, 我们最快也要在二十分钟后才能赶到
Sir, we're still two-zero minutes away at top speed.
好吧, 那样的话, 你们的时间不多了
赶快到这里来
Well, in that case, your timing sucks.
Get here as soon as you can.
你需要我才能离开这个星球
You need me to get off this planet.
只有我才能开动那艘飞船
I'm the only one who can fly that ship.
我只需要你的手来操作那些控制器就可以了
I will use your dead hands to operate its controls.
少校?
Major?
McKay!
我现在该怎么办?
What do I do now?
一直开火, 直到打完你所有的子弹!
Keep firing everything you've got!
好了, 现在呢?
Okay, now what?
重新装弹
Reload.
我们看到到他们在星球上的生命信号了
We're picking up their life signs on the planet.
向他们直飞过去
Head straight for them.
长官, 我们在瞄准镜中看到你了
Sir, we're picking you up on the aim.
没有子弹了!
No more bullets!
Ford, 朝着你所看到的最大的生命信号开火
Ford, lock onto the biggest
life-sign signals you can see and fire.
不行, 长官. 你们太近了!
Negative, sir. You're too close!
这是命令, 中尉
执行吧!
That's an order, Lieutenant.
Do it!
对准那个目标开火
Fire on that target.
McKay, 快跑!
McKay, run!
McKay?
还在这里!
Still here!
长官, 我是Ford
Sir, this is Ford.
目标消失了
The target is gone.
很好, 正是时候
Well, it's about damn time.
我们是尽快赶来的, 不能再快了, 少校
We got here as soon as we could, Major.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
多谢
Thanks.
不客气, 长官
You're welcome, Sir.
我们几分钟后就到
We'll be there in just a few minutes.
我们可以等
We can wait.
谢谢
Thanks.
Yeah. 你也一样
你还好吧?
Yeah. You too.
You okay?
除了这个和几根破碎的肋骨...
Other than this and a few cracked ribs...
Gall怎么样?
What about Gall?
不好
No.
你们可能必须合力把这个飞船恢复原状
尽你所能把防护罩关掉
You'll have to put the ship back together,
provided you could disarm the shield.
好的
Fine.
只要我们可以回家
As long as we get to go home.
你可以驾驶
You can drive.
噢, 谢谢
Oh, thank you.